Are you the kind of person who needs a pristine, orderly environment for you to feel relaxed?
你是那种需要一个整洁、有序的环境才能感到放松的人吗？
Or perhaps being surrounded by your clutter isn't a big deal – it might even bring you comfort.
或者，被自己的杂物环绕并不是什么大事——它甚至可能给你带来舒适。
'Professional organisers', who help people declutter their space, have grown in popularity in recent years, particularly on the internet.
近年来，帮助人们整理空间的"专业整理师"越来越受欢迎，尤其是在互联网上。
But does shedding your possessions always make you happier?
但是，丢弃你的物品总是让你更快乐吗？
Or, does clutter matter?
还是说，杂乱没关系？
Living in a messy space can have various negative effects on our lives.
生活在一个凌乱的空间里会对我们的生活产生各种负面影响。
For example, a study called 'No Place Like Home' by Repetti and Saxbe, found that mothers with messy homes had higher levels of the stress hormone cortisol and an increased depressed mood throughout the day.
例如，雷佩蒂和萨克斯贝的一项名为《没有像家一样的地方》的研究发现，家凌乱的母亲压力激素皮质醇水平更高，并且全天抑郁情绪加重。
Messy homes can also make it harder to fall asleep, according to the 2021 study 'The association between sleep and late life hoarding', and no one wants that!
2021年的研究《睡眠与晚年囤积行为之间的关联》也表明，凌乱的家会使入睡更加困难，没有人想要这样！
So perhaps Marie Kondo, author of 'The Life-Changing Magic of Tidying', was on to something when she said, "tidying can transform your life".
因此，也许《怦然心动的人生整理魔法》一书的作者玛丽·近藤所说的"整理可以改变你的人生"是有道理的。
To achieve Kondo's style of minimalism, she recommends gathering all your things together, choosing which items 'spark joy' and then discarding the rest.
为了实现近藤式的极简主义，她建议把你所有的东西集中在一起，选择哪些物品"能激发喜悦"，然后丢弃其余的。
Some may find it invigorating to begin again on a clean slate, while others, particularly extreme hoarders, can find the process anxiety-inducing, because of an attachment to their belongings.
有些人可能会觉得从头再来令人精神振奋，而其他人，尤其是极度囤积者，可能会因为对财物的依恋而觉得这个过程会引发焦虑。
Then there are those who simply enjoy collecting.
还有一些人就是喜欢收藏。
Vintage style expert Kate Beavis has a home filled with handbags, toys, phones and cookware from the 1960s.
复古风格专家凯特·比维斯的家里摆满了20世纪60年代的手提包、玩具、电话和炊具。
Others may call this clutter, but she argues that minimalist homes are "boring and bland".
别人可能称之为杂物，但她认为极简主义的家"无聊乏味"。
Some items may not have a practical use, but instead hold sentimental value, and spark joy in a nostalgic way.
有些物品可能没有实际用途，但却具有情感价值，并以怀旧的方式激发喜悦。
And things that "evoke happy memories are valuable, especially to people with memory problems," says Chris Stiff, senior lecturer in psychology at Keele University.
基尔大学心理学高级讲师克里斯·斯蒂夫说，"唤起快乐回忆的东西是有价值的，尤其对患有记忆问题的人而言。"
Maybe a giant mess isn't all bad.
也许乱的一团糟并非全是坏事。
And as Albert Einstein once said, "If a cluttered desk is a sign of a cluttered mind, of what, then, is an empty desk a sign?"
正如阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦曾经说过的："如果一张凌乱的桌子是混乱思维的标志，那么，一张空桌子又是什么的标志呢？"